{
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "React is a JavaScript library for building ___.",
      "options": {
        "1": "User interface",
        "2": "Connectivity",
        "3": "Database",
        "4": "Design Platform"
      },
      "ans": "1"
    },
    {
      "question":
        "User interface developed with React is made of small and isolated pieces of code called ___.",
      "options": {
        "1": "Hook",
        "2": "Function",
        "3": "Snippet",
        "4": "Component"
      },
      "ans": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the two main types of components in React.js?",
      "options": {
        "1": "Class based and functional",
        "2": "Functional and stateful",
        "3": "UI and container",
        "4": "Presentational and container"
      },
      "ans": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "A React component takes in parameters called ___?",
      "options": {
        "1": "Attributes",
        "2": "Events",
        "3": "Props",
        "4": "Children"
      },
      "ans": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "To write HTML in react we make use of ___?",
      "options": {
        "1": "React.createElement()",
        "2": "JSX",
        "3": "HTTP",
        "4": "XML"
      },
      "ans": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "JSX Stands for ___?",
      "options": {
        "1": "JavaScript Extension",
        "2": "JavaScript XML",
        "3": "JavaScript Extreme",
        "4": "JavaScript XScript"
      },
      "ans": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "React DOM uses ___ case property naming convention?",
      "options": {
        "1": "Pascal",
        "2": "Snake",
        "3": "Camel",
        "4": "Kebab"
      },
      "ans": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "___ are the smallest building blocks of React apps.",
      "options": {
        "1": "JSX",
        "2": "Elements",
        "3": "Tags",
        "4": "Components"
      },
      "ans": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "Applications built with just React usually have a single ___?",
      "options": {
        "1": "Parent Node",
        "2": "Components",
        "3": "Constructor",
        "4": "Root DOM node"
      },
      "ans": "4"
    },
    {
      "question":
        "Which component lifecycle method runs after the component output has been rendered to the DOM",
      "options": {
        "1": "componentMounted()",
        "2": "componentWillUnmount()",
        "3": "componentDidRender()",
        "4": "componentDidMount()"
      },
      "ans": "4"
    }
  ]
}